<feed>
  <entry>
    <date>2025-12-24</date>
    <tag>New Version</tag>
    <title>Version 1.2.3</title>
    <summary>Seasonal Update - Christmas Arrives! (Part III | Final)</summary>
    <headerImage>https://www.toledoblade.com/image/2009/03/07/600x_q90_a4-3_cTCjpg/Halo-Wars-comes-up-short-in-popular-series.jpg</headerImage>
    <markdown>
    <![CDATA[
[Performance]
Texture optimization pass completed using external research techniques:
Mod size reduced from 953 MB → 781 MB, improving efficiency without sacrificing quality.

[Adjustments]
Frontend overlay updated — replaced the wreath with a more subtle frost overlay for a cleaner winter aesthetic.
Blizzards added to Fort Deen and Frontier:
Snow particles now appear across nearly all regions, creating a fully immersive winter atmosphere.
Controller Sentinel creeps added to Sentry as part of the Rebels faction:
4 Controller Sentinels can now be found scattered around key points of interest.
Leader Power icon updates:
Ravakteus — Overwatch Protocol now has a unique icon.
Spartan Jacob — Tactical Override now has a unique icon.
The Tyrant (Rtapa’ Vonamai) — Rapid Advance now has a unique icon.
The Mercenary (Syzo ’Vrarum) — Cloak Tower Drop now has a unique icon.
All UNSC and Vanquished units reskinned with festive accent highlights:
Subtle gold, red, and rich green detailing applied across units.
Team colors remain fully identifiable to preserve gameplay clarity.

[Notess]This concludes the Christmas Update; thank you for playing, and happy holidays!!!]]></markdown>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <date>2025-12-16</date>
    <tag>New Version</tag>
    <title>Version 1.2.2</title>
    <summary>Seasonal Update - Christmas Arrives! (Part II)</summary>
    <headerImage>https://www.toledoblade.com/image/2009/03/07/600x_q90_a4-3_cTCjpg/Halo-Wars-comes-up-short-in-popular-series.jpg</headerImage>
    <markdown>
    <![CDATA[
ALL maps have now been snow-covered, with nearly every surface fully retextured to embrace the winter theme.
Blizzards will begin rolling in as Christmas approaches, expected around December 20th–24th.
UNSC units and buildings redesigned with a festive Christmas aesthetic:
Team colors remain intact for clarity.
Units now feature gold, red, and rich green accents for a seasonal flair.
The Vanquished festive redesign is still in progress and will debut in a later update.
Map loading screens updated to reflect the Christmas theme; covers coming soon.
A large portion of the UI has been reskinned to match the holiday aesthetic.
Splash screen updated to take on a new festive holiday look.
A preview of an incoming blizzard may now be seen on Fort Deen, particularly near the center of the map.]]></markdown>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <date>2025-03-11</date>
    <tag>New Version</tag>
    <title>Version 1.2.1</title>
    <summary>Seasonal Update - Christmas Arrives!</summary>
    <headerImage>https://cdn2.steamgriddb.com/icon/2c7b84fa30f0cea96a90729afe2970a0.ico</headerImage>
    <markdown>
		<![CDATA[
Splash screen fully updated to reflect the Christmas theme.
All grass textures have been replaced with snow, giving most maps a festive winter appearance.
Maps and other features will continue to grow progressively snowier and colder as December approaches — stay tuned for more updates!]]></markdown>
  </entry>
</feed>
