<feed>
  <entry>
    <date>2025-03-28</date>
    <tag>New Version</tag>
    <title>Version 1.2.3</title>
    <summary>Boss phases now react to player composition and economy spikes.</summary>
    <headerImage>https://www.toledoblade.com/image/2009/03/07/600x_q90_a4-3_cTCjpg/Halo-Wars-comes-up-short-in-popular-series.jpg</headerImage>
    <markdown>
		<![CDATA[
[Going Forward...]
> Developer Comment: Following this update, the mod may not be updated for a little while. This is due to me choosing to remake the mod from scratch and implementing many game-wide changes in the process. However, this may not take as long as it might sound, as I will not have to remake any existing assets and would just need to reimport the majority of them. So why am I doing this then? Organization mostly, but also for the previously mentioned game-wide changes. Almost everything will be modified in some way, and changes of this scale are much easier to do from scratch. I do plan on keeping the vast majority of the content currently within the mod though, and there will be a multitude of new additions that come with the next update, including an overhaul for the United Rebel Front. Ideally, this should only take a few months, but motivation is also key and could cause that estimation to swing wildly.

[New Content]

= Firefight Game Mode =
> Firefight has been added! It's been ported mostly as-is from a template, though I did buff up the flood just for fun. It's nowhere near done, and will definitely be getting worked on over time.

[Balance Adjustments]
== GLOBAL ==

- Marines -
> Nerf/Bugfix: Fixed "double dipping" of damage upgrades.
> Buff/Bugfix: Changed the damage and health multipliers obtained through all upgrades from [1.15x] to [1.25x] to be consistent with other units.

- Grunt/Jackal Squad -
> Nerf/Bugfix: Fixed "double dipping" of damage upgrades.
> Buff/Bugfix: Changed the damage and health multipliers obtained through all upgrades from [1.15x] to [1.25x] to be consistent with other units.

- Vulture -
> Buff/Bugfix: Now gains increased statistics when upgraded to mirror other units in the game.
> Adjustment: Modified the 'Attackrate' value on the cannons to mirror that of other fast firing weapons. This SHOULD be a buff...
> Buff: Increased the damage per second of the cannons from [140] to [160]. (~14% increase)

- Covenant Gravity Lift -
> Nerf: Cost to recall leader increased from [100] to [150] (50% increase)

= Captain Cutter =

- Hellbringers-
> Nerf: Reduced damage multiplier towards buildings from [1.25] to [1]. Note that they still deal twice as much damage to buildings compared to Flamethrowers.

- Sunray 1-1 -
> Rework: Adjusted EMP MAC Blast damage multipliers against most unit types; will now deal significantly less damage [~75%] to infantry targets and buildings. Damage against most vehicles has been unchanged, though heavy vehicles and uber units will take slightly more damage than before.
> Nerf/Bugfix: Changed the damage and health multipliers obtained through all upgrades from [1.5x] to [1.25x] to be consistent with other units.

= Sergeant Forge =
- Grizzly -
> Developer Comment: Spartans may not have been the problem after all; Grizzlies seem to be overperforming even without being occupied by them. Hopefully this brings them down a bit further.
> Nerf: Reduced base health to [14000] from [15000]. (~6.67% reduction)
> Nerf: Reduced stats gained passively from being a Grizzly. Note that Grizzlies also gain stats from Scorpion upgrades, and those are unaffected. The multipliers for health and damage have been reduced from [1.95x] and [2.44x] to [1.5x] and [1.75x], respectively.
> Nerf: Reduced Canister Shell base damage from [2000] to [1800]. Note that Canister Shells fired from Grizzlies will still deal more damage than those fired from Scorpions due to upgrade damage multipliers. (10% reduction)

- Sergeant Forge -
> Nerf: Reduced Anvil Round damage from [3000] to [2500] as a precautionary measure regarding veterancy. (~16.67% decrease)
> Nerf/Bugfix: Changed the damage and health multipliers obtained through the first 2 upgrades from [1.5x] to [1.25x] to be consistent with other units.

= Professor Anders =
- Anders' Cryo-clops -
> Buff/Bugfix: Changed the damage and health multipliers obtained through upgrades from their previous inconsistent values to [1.25x] to be consistent with other units.

- Cryo Bomb -
> Nerf: Can no longer instantly kill heavy air units. Ravens, Pelicans, Phantoms, Spirits, Sylphs, and Vultures are currently the only heavy air units.

== SWORDS OF SANGHELIOS ==

- Artillery Emplacement -
> Nerf: Maximum count reduced to [4]. (Previously [5])

- Elite Marauders -
> Nerf: Reduced base damage of each squad member from [37] to [27.75]. (25% decrease)

- Main Base -
> Buff/Rework: Now has scaling damage resistance identical to UNSC bases.
> Nerf/Rework: Health reduced from [20000/40000/80000] to [10000/15000/20000] (now mirrors UNSC base health)

- Sylph -
> Buff/Bugfix: Now gains increased statistics when upgraded to mirror other units in the game
> Adjustment: Modified the 'Attackrate' value on the cannons to mirror that of other fast firing weapons. This SHOULD be a buff...
> Buff: Increased the damage per second of the cannons from [140] to [160]. (~14% increase)

- Vergil -
> Buff: Self healing delay reduced by [50%], and the heal now has an associated particle effect.
> Nerf: Reduced healing rate by [15%]. (Self heal is unaffected)

- Weevil Strike (Leader Power) -
> Developer Comment: I will continue to pay extra attention to feedback regarding the leader power and its accessibility. I am still looking for ways to make it better without making it overbearing.
> Buff/Community Request: Resource cost reduced to [25] Supplies per use, from [150] (~83.34% Reduction!)
> Buff: Recharge time reduced from [120] seconds to [90] seconds. (25% Reduction)

- Wraith -
> Nerf/Bugfix: Made the Volley ability much more inaccurate like it was intended to be. (~66% Reduction)

[Bugfixes]

> Fixed old description used by the Improved Requisitions upgrade.
> Updated the description of the Serpent Hunter upgrade so that it no longer refers to Swarmlords as 'Mythic'.
> Fixed the Swords of Sanghelios being unable to use the special leader powers granted by the Methane Refinery garrison.
> Fixed a bug where the Rebel Saboteur would leave out of the wrong side of the base, often getting itself stuck inside buildings.
> "Fixed" the Rebel Saboteur training voiceline not playing by giving it the Cyclops training line instead. It still uses Brute voicelines for everything else however.
> Fixed an oversight where Vergil could be instantly killed with a Cryo Bomb.
> Fixed a bug where Grizzlies trained by the AI were not being affected by upgrades.
> Fixed Skymaster 'Dalamen being completely unaffected by upgrades.
> Fixed the unit icon not updating when upgrading warthogs with the flame warthog skin.
> Fixed Swords of Sanghelios minibase structures not appearing on the minimap.
> Fixed the AI creating the wrong buildings on minibase slots.

[Minor/Misc Changes]

> Updated description of transport powers so that they can be universally applicable.
> Modified firing sounds for the Anti-Air Wraith.
> Changed the appearance of locked down Anti-Air Wraith projectiles when firing at air units.
> Made it slightly more apparent whenever the Anti-Air Wraith is "unlocking" itself through the addition of cobra unlock sounds.
> Updated descriptions of disabled skulls.
> Minor update to Old Mombassa that allows the pathfinding to recognize the new obstacles.
> The AI can now build Reactors and Temples on minibases.
> Updated Healthbars to be more dynamic color-wise.
> Tweaked the launch screen text.

[Known Issues]
> It seems that the addition of many new custom particles is the most frequent cause of crashes at this time. It isn't shoddy implementation that causes this, but rather it's the number of **different** particles being loaded simultaneously. This is especially noticeable when the Mammoth and/or Draugr are on the field, as both of them are particularly particle heavy. This is unfixable without either disabling/removing a lot of the "cool" particles throughout the mod or by a future tool development that allows us to change an internal limit regarding particles. (This also means that any future additions will not have any custom particles made specifically for them, no matter how much they might end up needing one)
> ODSTs and Marauders are unable to garrison 1 slot garrisons. This will be remedied soon with a Garrison Rework.
> Vergil does not gain a defensive aura with his final upgrade if he is already on the field. This is a bug with the game regarding script activation, and I currently don't have the script knowledge to fix this.
> Elite Marauders are intended to be able to fire off their ability from long range, yet for some reason they often won't. A fix has yet to be discovered.
> The Rebel Saboteur training animation behaves very weirdly. I can't do much about this with the current state of the tools unfortunately.
> The Rebel AI occasionally breaks and decides to not build anything for the duration of a match. I have no idea why they do this, and I've tried everything I could think of to fix it.
> Sometimes the AI will decide that upgrades are overrated and just not upgrade certain units over the course of the game. If anyone finds a fix please let me know!]]></markdown>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <date>2025-03-11</date>
    <tag>New Version</tag>
    <title>Version 1.2.2</title>
    <summary>Added optional rally pings and clearer co-op objectives.</summary>
    <headerImage>https://cdn2.steamgriddb.com/icon/2c7b84fa30f0cea96a90729afe2970a0.ico</headerImage>
    <markdown>
		<![CDATA[
[New Content]

== SWORDS OF SANGHELIOS ==

- AI SUPPORT -
> The Swords of Sanghelios now have AI support! Like the Rebels however, they are incapable of using the leader power. This is a limitation I will attempt to fix later on once I reverse engineer how Leader Overhaul did it.

[Balance Adjustments]
== GLOBAL ==

- Grizzly -
> Developer Comment: While Grizzlies are in a much better spot now then they were previously, they still seem to be doing quite a lot of damage when controlled by Spartans. These changes aim to further reduce their overpowered nature when under spartan control.
- Nerf: Reduced base damage of main cannons from [200] to [175] (12.5% decrease)
- Nerf: Reduced base damage of canister shell from [2350] to [2000]. This is now identical to the base canister shell damage of the Scorpion. (~15% decrease)

= Captain Cutter =
- Sunray 1-1 -
> Minor Rework: Internally Sunray 1-1 is a complete mess (and for the most part, still is). Their damage values were all over the place; some attacks did very little, while others did way too much... Their attacks now deal much more reasonable damage, and hopefully they are more balanced then they were before. It would be difficult to properly describe these adjustments since the numbers are all over, so I'll summarize it as "they do a lot less damage, but they MIGHT be balanced now".
+ Buff/Bugfix: Upgraded EMP Mac Blasts now properly full stun targets.

- MAC Blast -
- Nerf: Cooldown time increased by [60 seconds], bringing it to a [4 minute] recharge. This is a soft nerf for triple and quad MAC Blasts.

- UNITED REBEL FORCES -
- Rebel Commando -
+ Buff/Bugfix: Now collects crates at 3x the speed, to match the same collection speed bonus of other leader units.

== SWORDS OF SANGHELIOS ==
> Developer Comment: I will continue to pay extra attention to feedback regarding the leader power and its accessibility. I was initially very hesitant on giving it too much, but I forgot to take fully upgraded MAC Blasts in account when attempting to balance them.

- ALL BUILDINGS -
+ Buff: To compensate for the lack of shields, the health of all base buildings have been increased to match their UNSC counterparts. The Artillery Emplacement in particular significantly benefits from this buff, going from [5000 HP] to [20000 HP]. The only exception is command center itself, which has more health then the UNSC equivalent by default.

- Artillery Emplacement -
+ Buff/Rework: Adjusted cost scaling from [250 (+250)] to [175 (+125)], hopefully making the production of multiple Emplacements more accessible while retaining the cost escalation.

- Ghost -
+ Buff: Cost reduced from [175 Supplies] to [150 Supplies]. (~14% Reduction)

- Phantom Gunboat -
> Developer Comment: Forgot to take a few factors in account when giving the Gunboat the proper uber stats. Didn't mean to make it stronger then anything else in the mod!
> Rework/Community Request: Main gun damage adjusted to have ramping damage over time, starting at [50% damage] but eventually it will reach [400% damage] over the course of 20 seconds of constant fire.
- Nerf: Main gun base damage reverted back to [250] (400% decrease!)

- Vergil -
+ Buff: Decreased training time by [15 seconds], bringing it to [45 seconds].
+ Buff: Lowered training cost by [150 supplies], making him only cost [300].
- Nerf: To compensate for these reductions on top of balance issues, Vergil's healing rate has been reduced by [10%].

- Weevil Strike (Leader Power) -
+ Buff: Upgrades now have the same cost scaling as the Covenant leaders. This means they have gone from [700>1000>1400 Supplies] to [300>500>700 Supplies] in terms of cost.
+ Buff: Research Time has similarly been reduced to match the times of the Covenant leader powers as well, going from [60>60>60 seconds] to [20>40>60 seconds].
+ Buff: Now recharges [30 seconds] faster then before, bringing down the recharge time to exactly [2 minutes]. For comparison, a vanilla UNSC leader power takes 3 minutes to recharge.

- Tankmaster -
+ Buff: Cost reduced from [525 Supplies] to [500 Supplies]. (~5% Reduction)

[Bugfixes]

> Fixed an issue with the hitbox of the Swords of Sanghelios main base, which made it almost impossible to damage.
> Fixed the Anti-Air Wraith being unable to fire while locked down.
> Reverted a debug change that made the Saboteur upgrades research extremely fast.
> Fixed an issue where the side turrets on the Phantom Gunboat would deal 0 damage.

[Minor/Misc Changes]

> Adjusted a few particularly long descriptions.
> Made numerous modifications to a few of the AI files. They should be vocal about the (custom) units they are making, and they should be upgrading things they weren't upgrading previously. The potentially affected units are: Wolverines, Ghosts, Choppers, and Locusts, as well as Wraiths, Locusts, Banshees, and Vampires for the Brute Chieftain. I also attempted to fix the Rebel AI breaking occasionally; in testing it seems to have done the trick...
> Imported animations for the Rebel Saboteur to use while dying and being deployed from Pelicans. I attempted to get one for the training animation, but technical difficulties made that unfeasible.


[Known Issues]
> The addition of many sorts of custom particle effects into the mod seems to have unintentionally made the game pretty unstable. This is especially noticeable when the Mammoth or Draugr are on the field, as both of them are particularly particle heavy. This is unfixable without either removing a lot of the "cool" particles throughout the mod, or by a future development that allows us to change an internal limit regarding particles. (This also means that any future additions will not have any custom particles made specifically for them, no matter how much they might end up needing one)
> ODSTs and Marauders are unable to garrison 1 slot garrisons. This will be remedied soon with a Garrison Rework.
> Vergil does not gain a defensive aura with his final upgrade if he is already on the field. This is a bug with the game regarding script activation, and I currently don't have the script knowledge to fix this.
> Elite Marauders are intended to be able to fire off their ability from long range, yet for some reason they often won't. A fix has yet to be discovered.]]></markdown>
  </entry>
</feed>
